# Albert Aghajanyan, Software Development Engineer

#### **CONTACTS**

**Phone**: +374 95 89 87 95

Email: <u>albert.aghajanyan.swe@gmail.com</u>

**Telegram**: @albertaghajanyan

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Development Engineer with over 7 years of work experience, with more oriented in front end development. Over 5 years of experience in Node.JS, JavaScript/TypeScript, React.JS. Familiar with Java, Bash, Python, C/C++. Solid experience and understanding of functional programming, OOP, and design patterns. Designed database schemas with complex entity relationships. Utilized Agile/Scrum methodology to manage full life-cycle development of the project. Self-motivated, hardworking individual and has ability to work in a team and independently in any environment.

#### **TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY**

**Project** Planning, estimating, executing, managing and supervising teams, risk

management planning, cross-team collaborations

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML/CSS.

Familiar with Java, Bash, Python, C/C++.

Frameworks: Node.JS, Nest.JS, Express.JS, React.JS, Next.JS, MUI, Antd, Bootstrap,

Redux, Redux Thunk, Redux Toolkit, RTK Query, MobX, React Query,

React Hook Form, GraphQL, Socket.io, WebSockets

**DBMS:** PostgreSQL, MySQL

**ORMS:** Sequelize, Typeorm

Tools: Git, VIM, JIRA, Confluence, Github, Bitbucket, Visual Studio Code,

Xcode, Jenkins, Appium, Maven, npm

Methodologies: Object-Oriented Programming, Design Patterns (Singleton, Factory),

Architectural Patterns (MVC), Generic Programming, Agile/Scrum

Methodology

Other: Webpack, Docker, nginx, AWS, S3, Linux, macOS, UX/UI,

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **Project management**

- Mediation and problem-solving
- Estimating developers task and projects
- Communicating with other teams
- Resolving different technical issues
- Providing code review and best practices
- Managing and supervising teams

# JavaScript \ TypeScript

- Server-side development (Node.JS, Express.JS, Nest.JS, PostgreSQL/MySQL, Sequelize)
- Client-side development (React.JS, Next.JS Redux, Redux Thunk, Redux Toolkit, RTK Query, MobX, React Query, React Hook Form, GraphQL, Socket.io, WebSockets, Material-UI, Ant, Bootstrap)
- Interactive UI implementation (/React Query/Axios/Fetch/API/WebSockets)

#### DB: PostgreSQL, MySQL

- Design complex, normalized database schemas
- Development of triggers, design of indexes, and foreign key constraints for referential integrity

**Development methodologies** (Object-Oriented Programming, Design Patterns (Singleton, Factory, Builder), Architectural Patterns (MVC), Generic Programming, Agile/Scrum Methodology)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Zealous (Instigate mobile)

September 2017 - January 2019

# Software Development Engineer

UI testing of web and mobile apps. Used languages and technologies: Swift, XCTest, Java, Maven, Git, Cucumber, Selenium, Appium, Confluence

## Zealous (Instigate mobile)

January 2019 - September 2019

# Software Development Engineer

A system that allows companies to manage projects and employees. Quickly find suitable employees for new projects.

#### Responsibilities:

- Maintained frontend components
- Maintained backend
- Conducted code reviews;
- Fixed bugs;
- Provided daily report.

<u>Used languages and technologies:</u> JavaScript, Node.JS, React.JS, Redux Thunk, Antd, Express.JS, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Git.

## Zealous (Instigate mobile)

September 2019 - January 2020

## Software Development Engineer

Developed a system for moving things. Created 3 dashboards.

- 1. Agency dashboard (used by drivers)
- 2. Client dashboards (used by users who have things to move)
- 3. Customer dashboard (administrators used to manage the entire transportation process)

#### Responsibilities:

- Designed the frontend part of the application;
- Designed user experience, user interaction, responsive design,

- Performed work estimations.
- Provided monthly report.

<u>Used languages and technologies:</u> JavaScript, React.JS, Redux Thunk, SCSS, Google Map, Git.

## Zealous (Instigate mobile)

January 2020 - July 2022

# Software Development Engineer

A system for buying various products from freezers using a QR code. Developed different workspaces for different types of users (admins, providers, users...).

# Responsibilities:

- Designed and implemented the web app and database;
- Provided daily report.

<u>Used languages and technologies:</u> JavaScript/Typescript, Node.JS, React.JS, Axios, MobX, MUI, Express.JS, Sequelize, MySQL, Git, AWS, docker, nginx WebSocket.

## Flexy Global

*July 2022 - August 2023* 

#### Senior Software Development Engineer

A system for obtaining a state certificate for different types of companies. Developed different workspaces for different user types (30+ user types).

#### Responsibilities:

- Designed and implemented the web app;
- Designed user experience, user interaction, responsive and perfect pixel design,
- Performed work estimations.
- Provided daily report.

<u>Used languages and technologies:</u> JavaScript/Typescript, React.JS, Next.JS, React Query, React Hook Form, GraphQL, MUI, Webpack, Git, Bitbucket, AWS, docker.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and Informatics
State Engineering University of Armenia